Curriculum Vitae

Email: A.F.Banaji "at" lboro.ac.uk

Website: <u>amlan-banaji.github.io</u>

Nationality: UK

Research Associate in Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University's mathematics department since March 2023

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My main research interests are in geometry and analysis related to fractal sets and measures. These 'fractals' exhibit complexity over a wide range of scales, and often arise in a natural dynamical way, such as via (conformal or non-conformal) iterated function systems. Currently, I am especially interested in the rate of decay of the Fourier transform of stationary measures for such systems. I have also done a lot of work exploring different ways one can define 'dimension,' to provide refined information about the global or local scaling properties of classes of sets or measures. I enjoy finding connections between these topics and other areas of mathematics such as number theory and probability theory.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

Preprints:

- 10. S. Baker and A. Banaji. *Polynomial Fourier decay for fractal measures and their pushforwards*. arXiv
- 9. A. Banaji, J. M. Fraser, I. Kolossváry and A. Rutar. *Assouad spectrum of Gatzouras–Lalley carpets*.
- 8. A. Banaji, A. Rutar and S. Troscheit. *Interpolating with generalized Assouad dimensions*, Submitted. arXiv
- 7. A. Banaji and I. Kolossváry. *Intermediate dimensions of Bedford–McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence*, Submitted. <u>arXiv</u>
- 6. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Assouad type dimensions of infinitely generated self-conformal sets* Submitted to Nonlinearity. <u>arXiv</u>

Published:

- 5. A. Banaji. *Generalised intermediate dimensions* **Monatshefte für Mathematik** 202 (2023), 465–506. <u>arXiv</u>
- 4. A. Banaji. *Metric spaces where geodesics are never unique* To appear in the **American Mathematical Monthly** 130 (2023), 747–754. <u>arXiv</u>
- 3. A. Banaji and J. M. Fraser. *Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors* **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society** 376 (2023), 2449–2479. <u>arXiv</u>
- 2. A. Banaji and H. Chen. *Dimensions of popcorn-like pyramid sets* **Journal of Fractal Geometry** 10 (2023), 151–169. <u>arXiv</u>
- 1. A. Banaji and A. Rutar. *Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions* **Annales Fennici Mathematici** 47 (2022), 939–960. <u>arXiv</u>

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

PhD Mathematics

2019–2023

Thesis: "Interpolating between Hausdorff and box dimension" (defended May 2023)

With the **Analysis Research Group**

 $\textbf{Topic:} \ \ \textbf{Fractal geometry and dimension theory}$

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Fully funded by the **Leverhulme Trust**

University of St Andrews 2018–2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

<u>Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains</u> (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by <u>Professor Kenneth Falconer</u>)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015–2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

PRIZES AND GRANTS

- 2023–4: Awarded £500 LMS Travel Grant for Early Career Researchers to visit the University of Oulu
- 2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best MSc student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given at least 30 talks (see https://amlan-banaji.github.io/files/BanajiTalks.pdf) at conferences and seminar series including:

- Fractal Geometry (celebrating Prof. Kenneth Falconer's 70th birthday, ICMS, Edinburgh, 4/7/23)
- Multifractal analysis and self-similarity (CIRM, Marseille, 30/6/23)
- <u>Diophantine Approximation, Dynamics, and Fractals</u> (Exeter, 22/6/23)
- Thermodynamic Formalism: Non-additive Aspects and Related Topics (Będlewo, 16/5/23)
- Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems Seminar (Bristol, 13/3/23)
- Analysis Seminar (Edinburgh, 13/3/23)
- One World Fractals (online, 18/1/23)
- Mathematics Research Day (St Andrews, 1/12/22)
- Szenzhen Technology University Mathematics Colloquium (China (online), inaugural talk, 22/10/22)
- Fractals and Related Fields IV (Porquerolles, France, 5/9/22)
- Geometry of Deterministic and Random Fractals (Budapest University of Technology and Economics, 30/6/22)
- Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting (ICMS, Edinburgh (30/3/22) and online (19/3/21))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, 30/5/22 and 1/3/21)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, 22/3/23, 3/5/22, 12/10/21, 20/4/21, 30/6/20)

EXPERIENCE

Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

Most recent student feedback score: 1.5 on a scale from 1 to 5 (where 1 is highest).

2019–2022: MT2502 Analysis (10 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- 2018–2022: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with G5 Education, Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.

SERVICE

- 2023–4: Co-organiser of Workshop on Ergodic Theory and Fractal Geometry at Loughborough University
- 2023–present: Co-organiser of the Loughborough University Dynamical Systems Seminar
- 2022—present: **Referee** for *Proc. Roy. Soc. Edinburgh Sect. A* and *Colloq. Math.* and *Amer. Math. Monthly* and *J. Math. Anal. Appl.*
- 2022: **Organiser** of St Andrews Analysis Reading Group
- 2021: **Co-organiser** of the Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews.
- 2019–2021: **Treasurer** of St Andrews Mindfulness Society.

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES